A Guide to the Records of Sigma Xi, the Scientific Research Society, Virginia Chapter, 1924-1960 (1985)
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Records of Sigma Xi, the Scientific Research Society, Virginia Chapter 1924-1960 [1985]
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-24/23/1.871
This collection consists of 11 boxes.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the library as a gift on 1985 July 30.
Scope and Content Information
Collection includes correspondence; treasurer's records; secretary's records; membership records; national lecturers; President and visitors prize; and miscellaneous and printed material.
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Correspondence-General 1925-1933 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - A-C 1925-1933 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - D-H 1925-1933 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - H-Mc 1925-1933 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - M-P 1925-1933 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - R-Z 1925-1933 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - General 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - General 1936-1937 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - General 1938-1939 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence - General 1940-1941 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - General 1942 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - General 1943-1944 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - General 1945 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - General 1946 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - General 1947 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - General 1948 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - General 1949 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - General 1950-1951 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - General 1952-1953 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - Annual Meeting 1953 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Initiation 1935 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Installation 1948-1953 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Other Chapters 1935-1937 (Box 3)
- Series II: Treasurer's Records
  - Treasurer 1933-1939 (Box 3)
  - Treasurer 1939-1940 (Box 3)
  - Treasurer 1940-1941 (Box 3)
  - Treasurer 1941-1942 (Box 3)
  - Treasurer 1942-1943 (Box 3)
  - Treasurer 1943-1945 (Box 3)
  - Treasurer 1945-1946 (Box 3)
  - Treasurer-Bills and Receipts 1927-1945, 4 folders (Box 3)
- Series III: Secretary's Records
  - Secretary and Treasurer Record Book 1924-1933 (Box 4)
  - Secretary and Treasurer Record Book 1934-1943 (Box 4)
  - Secretary and Treasurer Record Book 1944-1951 (Box 4)
  - Annual Reports 1938-1947, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Secretary's Report 1942-1943 (Box 4)
  - Secretary's Report-Spring 1943 1943 (Box 4)
  - Secretary's Report-By-Laws 1985 (Box 4)
- Series IV: Membership Records
  - Membership - Comprehensive List 1924-1942 (Box 5)
  - Membership - I.D. Cards. 1924-1947 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1924 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Nominations 1924 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1925 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Nominations 1925 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1926 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Nominations 1926 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1927 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Nominations 1927 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1928 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Nominations 1928 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1930 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1931 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Nominations 1931 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1932 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Nominations 1932 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1933 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Nominations 1933 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1934 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Nominations 1934 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1935 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Nominations 1935 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Nominations for National Officers 1935-1936 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1936 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Nominations 1936 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1937 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Nominations 1937 (Box 5)
  - Membership - Transfer Out 1936-1937 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1938 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Nominations 1938 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1939 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Nominations 1939 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1940 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Nominations 1940 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1941 (Box 6)
  - Membership - List 1941 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Nominations 1941 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1942 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Nominations 1942 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1943 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Nominations 1943 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1944 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Nominations 1944 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1945 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Nominations 1945 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1946 (Box 6)
  - Membership - List 1946 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Nominations 1946 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1947 (Box 6)
  - Membership - List 1947 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Nominations 1947 (Box 6)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1948 (Box 7)
  - Membership - List 1948 (Box 7)
  - Membership - Nominations 1948 (Box 7)
  - Membership - Transfers In 1948-1949 (Box 7)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1949 (Box 7)
  - Membership - List 1949 (Box 7)
  - Membership - New Members 1949 (Box 7)
  - Membership - Nominations 1949 (Box 7)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1950 (Box 7)
  - Membership - List 1950 (Box 7)
  - Membership - Nominations 1950 (Box 7)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1951 (Box 7)
  - Membership - List 1951 (Box 7)
  - Membership - Nominations 1951 (Box 7)
  - Membership - Transfers In 1951 (Box 7)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1952 (Box 8)
  - Membership - List 1952 (Box 8)
  - Membership - Nominations 1952 (Box 8)
  - Membership - Transfers In 1952 (Box 8)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1953 (Box 8)
  - Membership - New Members 1953 (Box 8)
  - Membership - Nominations 1953 (Box 8)
  - Membership - Nominations of Alumni 1953 (Box 8)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1954 (Box 8)
  - Membership - New Members 1954 (Box 8)
  - Membership - Nominations 1954 (Box 8)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1955 (Box 8)
  - Membership - New Members 1955 (Box 8)
  - Membership - Nominations 1955 (Box 8)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1956 (Box 8)
  - Membership - New Members 1956 (Box 8)
  - Membership - Nominations 1956 (Box 9)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1957 (Box 9)
  - Membership - New Members 1957 (Box 9)
  - Membership - Nominations 1957 (Box 9)
  - Membership - Transfers In and Out 1957-1959 (Box 9)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1958 (Box 9)
  - Membership - New Members 1958 (Box 9)
  - Membership - Nominations 1958 (Box 9)
  - Membership - Acceptance Letters 1959 (Box 9)
  - Membership - New Members 1959 (Box 9)
  - Membership - Nominations 1959 (Box 9)
- Series V: National Lecturers
  - National Lecturers - Dr. C. Speidel 1945 (Box 10)
  - National Lecturers - Dr. A. Gesell 1948 (Box 10)
  - National Lecturers - Dr. G. Corner 1949 (Box 10)
  - National Lecturers - Dr. G. Gamow 1951 (Box 10)
  - National Lecturers - Dr. D. Griffin 1952 (Box 10)
  - National Lecturers - Dr. C. Stern 1952 (Box 10)
  - National Lecturers - Dr. F. Bloch 1953 (Box 10)
  - National Lecturers - Dr. O. Roberts 1953 (Box 10)
  - National Lecturers - Dr. C. Zirkle 1954 (Box 10)
  - National Lecturers - Dr. P. Sears 1955 (Box 10)
  - National Lecturers - Dr. B. Skinner 1956 (Box 10)
- Series VI: President and Visitors Prize
  - President and Visitors Prize to 1948 (Box 10)
  - President and Visitors Prize 1948 (Box 10)
  - President and Visitors Prize 1949 (Box 10)
  - President and Visitors Prize 1950 (Box 10)
  - President and Visitors Prize 1951 (Box 10)
  - President and Visitors Prize 1952 (Box 11)
  - President and Visitors Prize 1953
  - President and Visitors Prize 1954
- Series VII: Miscellaneous and Printed Matter
  - Initiation Ritual 1932-1959
  - V.P.I. Award 1951-1952
  - Key 1924
  - Printed Material 1927-1985
  - Election Announcement Broadsides 1930-1960